

Leonardo Anyelo Rodriguez Martinez

Mechatronics Engineer Backend developer

Date of Birth 26.04.1993 In Colombia

Colombia 111041 Bogotá

Phone number: +57 3144369928

E-Mail leonardorm7@hotmail.com

Mechatronic Engineer with more than 6 years of experience in different fields of mechatronics and a strong focus on programming. Thanks to my university studies and personal projects, I have developed skills in programming languages such as Python, Java, C/C++, as well as frameworks like Django and FastApi. Currently, I am looking to focus on my career as a backend developer and take advantage of my experience and passion for programming to contribute to a high-performing team.



work experience

Robotics Teacher at Montessori British School (08/2021 - Present)

- Teach robotics classes in English to high school students from 6th to 11th grade.
- Teach programming languages: Python, C, C++, and Java.
- Design and creation of electronic circuits.
- Creation of the program to teach the Python language to 10th grade students.
- In parallel, I have been working on different programming projects, including programs for organizing files, process automation, data extraction and web development.

Subject Matter Expert and Bilingual Agent at Teleperformance (09/2019 - 08/2021)

• Analyze and organize LOB databases to offer analysis regarding the results obtained.

Design Engineer at Emprecol Mechanize (05/2019 - 09/2019)

- Mechanical design in CAD software for the manufacture of forming and sealing molds for pharmaceuticals.
- Design of plans in Solid Works for the manufacture of mechanical parts.
- Development of a fatigue study for mechanical reinforcements.

Mechatronics Engineer at Terra Group Consultants (01/2019 - 05/2019)

- Corrective and preventive maintenance of equipment for the measurement of resistivity in the ground (tellurometer).
- Carried out the manipulation and data collection of the equipment for the measurement of resistivity in the soil.
- Design and manufacture of electronic circuits for managing soil resistivity equipment.

Project Engineer, Entrepreneur at BH2 Robotics (04/2017 - 05/2019)

- Electronic and mechanical design.
- Microcontroller programming in Python, C, and C++.
- Design of electrical circuits, assembly of surface circuits.
- Robot appearance design.
- Mobile application design, and development of robots for interaction with people.

SOFTWARE MANAGEMENT

Python

Java

C/C++

Visual studio code

Git

Github

Django

FastAPI

Flask

Arduino

Eclipse

NetBeans

Raspberry Pi 3

Pic C

Dev C++

MicroC PRO

Labview

Matlab

MPLAB

Solid edge

Solid Works

Autodesk Inventor

AutoCAD

Proteus

Festo

fluid sim

step7

. Codesys

Unity

Adobe Illustrator

Vex IQ Robots

Mbots

RobotC

Here you will find a little bit of the many projects I have done:

Projects

https://github.com/Engleonardorm7

Assistant Project Engineer at Servicloro Group (05/2016 - 03/2017)

- Project design, simulation, and costing of projects.
- Drawing plans in Autodesk Inventor, AutoCAD, and Solid Works
- Preparation of mechanical and electrical drawings, automation, programming, and preparation of equipment operation manuals.

Electronic Technician at Security Access (11/2015 - 05/2016)

- Installation of fences, issuing and verifying machines for parking cards.
- Preventive and corrective maintenance of ATMs, checkpoints, and parking machines in general.
- Installation of cameras, maintenance of computers and printers.
- Microcontrollers programming.

Assistant of Design and Development Area at PELPAK (07/2014 - 02/2015)

• Assisted in programming diagrams.

Education

• Design of mechanical parts, and automation processes, with a focus on control of three-phase motors.

Education	
2/2010 - 10/2015	University: Universidad de San Buenaventura Mechatronics Engineering
2/2023	Online education platform: Platzi Git and GitHub Professional Course Backend Development career with Python and Django
10/2022	Coursera by IBM: Python for Data Science, AI & Development



Bogotá, Colombia. - 2.2023